Sung Pil Moon

Curriculum Vitae

Department of Human-Computer Interaction School of Informatics Indiana University, Indianapolis 719 Indiana Avenue, Walker Plaza, Suite 360 Indianapolis, IN 46202 <u>sungmoon@umail.iu.edu</u>
<u>http://bit.ly/sungmoon</u>
(317) 361 - 5563

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research lies in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), with primary interests in human behavior understanding (e.g., motivation and decision-making), and interactive system design in conjunction with information visualization, usability and user experience. In particular, my current research focuses on creating useful and effective information visualization tools (both web and mobile)

- To provide sustainable motivation to run more and more frequently in a context of running, so that users of the tool would be able to change their behaviors
- To help aware of local trends by showing meaningful and analytical visualized information extracted from social data (e.g., Twitter, and Facebook)
- To provide decision-ready visualized options for decision makers for more accurate and confident decision by reducing their cognitive burden in dynamic and uncertain situations.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Human-Computer Interaction School of Informatics, Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN	Graduation Expected in Aug. 2013
 Dissertation title (Tentative): HamkeRun: Mobile Information visualization tool for sustainable motivation in a context of running 	
 Committee Members: Mark S. Pfaff (Chair), Davide Bolchini, Amy Liu, & Kevin Rand. 	
Master of Information Technology in eBusiness	Aug. 2006
School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA	
Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering	Feb. 2004
Soongsil University, Seoul, Korea Republic	

RESEARCH & PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant, Indiana University, Indianapolis	
 Crystal project Develop a decision-making tool to enable decision-makers to attain deeper levels of option awareness and choose a robust option via visualizations of the decision space. Funded by MITRE research Corporation (www.mitre.org) Take a role for UI, front-end side development and usability 	Sep. 2012 – Current
 GRAPPA Decision Space information development project Developed a decision space information visualization tool which is a model-based simulator to aid first emergency responder providing visualization of multiple decision options for more accurate and confident decisions. Funded by MITRE research Corporation (www.mitre.org) Project number: 43MSR001-EA, 45MSR026-FA Took a role for UI, front-end side development and usability 	Sep. 2008 – Mar. 2011
 Top Health Trends project Developed an information visualization tool showing local health-related Twitter trends to aid daily jobs of health-related experts. Collaborated with MESH coalition (www.meshcoalition.org) Took a main role in developing UI, front-end side, collecting requirements, and conducting usability tests 	Nov.2011 - June 2012
 ANRORA (Aural Navigation Flow On Rich website Architecture) project A NSF-funded project investigating linkless navigation strategy as a new way to increase mobile user experience while on-the-move. Developed an interactive mobile prototype (both in high fidelity and android version) and conducted usability tests. 	Sep.2012 – Jan. 2013
 MARVAND project Developed a mobile application supporting disaster relief activities for onsite volunteers after natural disaster. Took a main role in developing UI, front-end side, collecting user / system requirements, and conducting usability tests 	Nov.2012- Feb.2013
 Teaching Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh Robot to the Rescue (RttR) class, Institute for Software Research (ISR) Led a course and offered a guidance of general introduction of robotics, and developed a simulator with C#-based Microsoft Robotics Studio framework to communicate between mechanical devices and simulation services 	Nov.2006 - May 2008

Web developer, Webtown Company, Cheju City, Korea

July 1997 – Aug. 1998

- Worked as a developer for e-business solutions, and as a web designer
- Developed Java-based web application framework and testing tool

PUBLICATIONS AND POSTERS

Publications

Moon, S. P., Liu, Y., Entezari, S., Pirzadeh, A., Pappas, A., & Pfaff, S. M. (accepted, to be published in May, 2013). Top Health Trends: An information visualization tool for awareness of local health trends. *10th International Conference on Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management (ISCRAM'13)*. Baden-Baden, Germany, May 12-15.

Moon, S. P., Liu, T., Powit, R., Kim, B.M., & Pfaff, S. M. (submitted on February 15, 2013). MARVAND: Mobile application for relief volunteering activity after natural disaster. *15th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services, MobileHCI, 2013*. Munich, Germany.

Pfaff, M. S., Klein, G. L., Drury, J. L., Moon, S. P., Liu, Y., & Entezari, S. O. (2012). Supporting complex decision making through option awareness. Journal of Cognitive Engineering and Decision Making, Advance online publication. doi: 10.1177/1555343412455799

Liu, Y., Moon, S. P., Pfaff, M. S., Drury, J. L., & Klein, G. L. (2011). Collaborative option awareness for emergency response decision making. Paper presented at the 8th Annual International Conference on Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management (ISCRAM), Lisbon, Portugal, May 2011.

Pfaff, M. S., Drury, J. L., Klein, G. L., More, L. D., Moon, S. P., & Liu, Y. (2010). Weighing decisions: Aiding emergency response decision making via option awareness. Proceedings of the 2010 IEEE International Conference on Technologies for Homeland Security (HST), 251-257.

Posters

Bolchini, D., Rohani Ghahari, R., George-Palilonis, J., Moon, S.P., Archibald, C., & Kaser, L. (2012, November). Eyes-free web browsing with linkless navigation. IUPUI Innovation to Enterprise Showcase & Forum, IUPUI Campus Center, Indianapolis (IN), November 28, 2012.

Pfaff, M.S., Liu, Y., Moon, S. P., Entezari, S. O (2012, May). Effects of human-computer trust on collaborative decision making in a simulated emergency response. Poster presented at the 24th Annual Convention of the Association for Psychological Science, Chicago, IL.

Pfaff, M.S., Moon, S. P., & Liu, Y. (2010, April). The GRaPPa lab: Supporting team decision making in complex environments. Poster presented at the IUPUI Research Day, Indianapolis, IN.

Luther, J., Moon, S. P., Davide, D., & Faiola, A. (2009, November). Advancing paper-in-screen prototyping: Evaluating and interacting with digital sketched designs. Presented at 2009 Indiana World Usability Day, Indianapolis, IN.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Graduate Research Assistantship, Indiana University, Indianapolis	2008 - Current
Scholarship for Talented Alumni Student from Soongsil University, Seoul, Korea	2012 - 2013
Scholarship for Talented Student, Ministry of Commerce, Industry and Energy of Korea	2005 – 2006

HCI AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

Design Methods

User-centered design, participatory design, ideation, affinity diagramming, scenarios, personas, information architecture, experience prototyping, technology probes

User Research

Ethnography, contextual inquiry, focus group, experience sampling method, usability testing, heuristic analysis, GOMS, cognitive walkthrough, wizard of OZ, survey design & data analysis

Prototyping

Sketching, low/mid/high fidelity prototyping, paper prototyping, experience prototyping, Flash, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Fluid UI

Development

Java (SCJP; Sun Certified Java Programmer), Javascript, HTML5, CSS, XML, jQuery Mobile, C#, C/C++, Adobe Flex web / mobile programming, Actionscipt, Map SDKs (GoogleMap, MapQuest, ESRIMap), MySQL, Kinvey (BaaS)

PATENT

System and Method for Producing Video Map

Attorney Docket Number N&N-114US, Application Number: 12258709